Guide to the Grace Cavalieri papers, 1945-2022 MS2007
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Employment, 1955-2007; Series 13
  - Teaching - St. Mary's College, 1992-2006 (Box 52, Folder 5)
  - Teaching - Tuscany Castle Arts Retreat, 2003 (Box 52, Folder 6)
  - Teaching - Venetia School, 10/24/1955 --02/23/1956 (Box 52, Folder 7)
  - Teaching - Workshops, 1970-2007 (Box 52, Folder 8)
  - Washington Writers' Publishing House, 1982-1996 (Box 52, Folder 9)
- Bunny and the Crocodile Press/Forest Woods Media Productions, Inc., 1986-2007; Series 14
  This series consists of administrative materials related to Grace Cavalieri's private press - the Bunny and Crocodile Press - and to her media production company - Forest Woods Media Productions, Inc. Materials include awards, financial information, drafts of works published by the Bunny and the Crocodile Press, documents pertaining to the distribution of works published or produced, and completed forms for Library of Congress catalog numbers, International Standard Book Numbers, and Books in Print citations.
  - Awards, 2002 (Box 52, Folder 10)
  - D.C. Commission on the Arts and Humanities, 2002 (Box 52, Folder 11)
  - Drafts, undated (Box 53, Folder 1)
  - Distribution, 1998-2005 (Box 53, Folder 2)
  - Humanities Council of Washington, D.C., 2005 (Box 53, Folder 3)
  - Library of Congress catalog card numbers, 1986-2005 (Box 53, Folder 4)
  - ISBN, 1986-1993 (Box 53, Folder 5)
  - General, 2001-2007 (Box 53, Folder 6)
  - R.R. Bowker / Books in Print, 1989-2006 (Box 53, Folder 7)
  - Tax exemption, 1990-2003 (Box 53, Folder 8)
- Photographs and negatives, 1985-2016; Series 15
  This series includes photographs and negatives related to Grace Cavalieri's professional and personal life that were separated by Cavalieri from other material. Subjects include Cavalieri and her family, events such as poetry readings and book signings, poets interviewed by Cavalieri, Cavalieri and poets in the studio recording "The Poet and the Poem," and the annual jazz and poetry benefit for radio station WPFW-FM.
  - Awards, 1998-2006 (Box 53, Folder 9)
  - Cavalieri, Grace, 1991 (Box 53, Folder 10)
  - Personal, 1990-2001 (Box 53, Folder 11)
  - Personal, undated (Box 93, Folder 9)
  - Photographs & Negatives, 1970; Series 15 (Box 104, Folder 10)
  - Photographs, 2016; Series 15 (Box 115, Folder 11)
  - Poet and the Poem - Engineer, 2001 (Box 53, Folder 12)
  - Poet and the Poem - Interviews [1/17], 1989-2007 (Box 53, Folder 13)
  - Poet and the Poem - Interviews [2/17], 1991 (Box 53, Folder 14)
  - Poet and the Poem - Interviews [3/17], 1992 (Box 54, Folder 1)
  - Poet and the Poem - Interviews [4/17], 1995 (Box 54, Folder 2)
  - Poet and the Poem - Interviews [5/17], 2002 (Box 54, Folder 3)
  - Poet and the Poem - Interviews [6/17], 2002 (Box 54, Folder 4)
  - Poet and the Poem - Interviews [7/17], 2004 (Box 54, Folder 5)
  - Poet and the Poem - Interviews [8/17], 2004 (Box 54, Folder 6)
  - Poet and the Poem - Interviews [9/17], 2005 (Box 54, Folder 7)
  - Poet and the Poem - Interviews [10/17], 2005 (Box 54, Folder 8)
  - Poet and the Poem - Interviews [11/17], 2006 (Box 54, Folder 9)
  - Poet and the Poem - Interviews [12/17], 2006 (Box 54, Folder 10)
  - Poet and the Poem - Interviews [13/17], 2006 (Box 54, Folder 11)
  - Poet and the Poem - Interviews [14/17], 2006 (Box 54, Folder 12)
  - Poet and the Poem - Interviews [15/17], 2006 (Box 54, Folder 13)
  - Poet and the Poem - Interviews [16/17], 2007 (Box 54, Folder 14)
  - Poet and the Poem - Interviews [17/17], undated (Box 54, Folder 15)
  - Poet and the Poem Photographs, undated (Box 93, Folder 13)
  - Poet and the Poem Photographs, 2007 (Box 93, Folder 14)
  - Unidentified, undated (Box 54, Folder 16)
  - Poets [1/8], 1985 (Box 54, Folder 17)
  - Poets [2/8], 1988-2006 (Box 54, Folder 18)
  - Poets [3/8], 1991 (Box 54, Folder 19)
  - Poets [4/8], 1991 (Box 54, Folder 20)
  - Poets [5/8], 1997-2005 (Box 54, Folder 21)
  - Poets [6/8], 2006 (Box 54, Folder 22)
  - Poets [7/8], undated (Box 54, Folder 23)
  - Poets [8/8], undated (Box 100, Folder 6)
  - Quilting the Sun Photographs, 02/2007 (Box 93, Folder 11)
  - St Mary's College, Maryland, 1989 (Box 54, Folder 24)
  - Tex Jernigan Sculpture, 2007 (Box 93, Folder 10)
  - Washington Writers Collection, undated (Box 93, Folder 12)
  - WPFW Benefit, undated (Box 54, Folder 25)
  - WPFW - Poetry and Jazz Benefit [1/6], 1988 (Box 55, Folder 1)
  - WPFW - Poetry and Jazz Benefit [2/6], 1992 (Box 55, Folder 2)
  - WPFW - Poetry and Jazz Benefit [3/6], undated (Box 55, Folder 3)
  - WPFW - Poetry and Jazz Benefit [4/6], undated (Box 55, Folder 4)
  - WPFW - Poetry and Jazz Benefit [5/6], undated (Box 55, Folder 5)
  - WPFW - Poetry and Jazz Benefit [6/6], undated (Box 55, Folder 6)
  - Various photographs of personal life as well as poetry events, undated; Series 15 (Box 106, Folder 6)
  - Photographs and Negatives, 1994 October 19; Series 15 (Box 110, Folder 8)
    Photo of Grace and Reed Whittemore and newspaper clipping.
  - Photographs and Negatives, undated; Series 15 (Box 110, Folder 9)
    Photographs of Reed Whittemore, Michael Glaser, William Meredith, Richard Harters, Henry Taylor, Rita Dove, Lucille Clifton, Reuben Jackson, Candace Katz, William Gilcher, Roland Flint, Robert Hass, Robert Sargent, Karen Alenier, Fareedah Allah,
- Web Archives, 2016-2022; Series 16
  This series contains a link to the web archived content associated with Grace Cavalieri.This includes the website for the program The Poet and the Poem hosted by the Library of Congress Library of Congress Poet and the Poem website and also Grace's person webpage. Grace Cavalieri website This web crawling started in 2016 and continues.
  The web is continually changing and each day content disappears. To capture this history for future researchers, this web archive contains snapshots of these websites, collected at regular points in time. Special Collections uses Archive-It, a service provided by the Internet Archive, for web archiving.
  In 2018 the Special Collections Research Center began to crawl Grace's webpage to capture her Poet and the Poem radio program when it moved from the Libray of Congress. Grace Cavalieri website Below is a list of the poets Grace has interviewed from 2017-April 2022 and provided in the GW web archive of her website. we will continue to add content as the crawling continues.
  Poet and the Poem 2022-2023 Series
  Eva Brann; Kondwani Fidel; Terence Winch; George Ella Lyon; Vailes Shepperd; Miho Kinnas; Maria Mazziotti Gillan; Annie Finch; Samuel Peralta; Melvin E. Brown
  Poet and the Poem 2021-2022 Series
  Ocean Vuong; Terence Winch; Lenard D. Moore; John Doe; Jerry Ward; Henry Crawford; Didi Menendez; Francisco Aragon; Tom Kirlin; Jona Colson and Caroline Bock; Jehanne Dubrow; Miles David Moore; Maggie Doherty; Cornelius Eady; Paul Bartlett; Y.S. Fing; Teri Ellen Cross Davis; Sandra Beasley; Fleda Brown; Jeanne Murray Franklin; Rion Amilcar Scott; Jiwon Choi; Lenny DellaRocca; David Keplinger; Sandra Yannone; Willie Perdomo; J.P. Dancing Bear; Anne Harding Woodworth; Richard Harteis and Tom Veys; Thomas Sayers Ellis
  Poet and the Poem 2020-2021 Series
  Barbara DeCesare; The Write Blend Poetry Collective; Pamela Murray Winters; Shirley J. Brewer; Garrett J. Brown; Temple Cone; Lauren K. Alleyne; Doritt Carroll; Yao Hoke Glover III; Meg Eden; George Bilgere; Robert Earl Price IN CONCERT; Robert Earl Price Interview; Danuta E. Kosk-Kosicka; Andrew McConnell Stott; Jody Bolz; Dr. Monifa A. Love; Jericho Brown; Jose Padua; Ann Bracken; Jesse N. Alexander; Jeffrey Coleman; Carolyn Joyner; Barbara Quick; Linda Joy Burke; Kim Roberts; Mecca Verdell; John O'Dell; Ned Balbo; Carolyn Forche
  Poet and the Poem 2019-2020 Series
  Panna Naik; Joanna Howard; Lisa Vihos; Fatemeh Keshavarz; Steve Leyva; Seema Reza; Judith Farr; Susan Orlean; Nancy Mitchell; celeste doaks; Robert Ertman; Joy Harjo; Natwar Gandhi; Mervyn Taylor; Jane Clarke; Rob Richmond
  Poet and the Poem 2018-2019 Series
  Dr. Xuhua Liang; Chad Frame; Erica Wright; David Gewanter; Wendy Lesser; Marcus Jackson; Michael Lally; Nin Andrews; Linda Pastan; Kyle Dargan; Virginia Smith; Kim Roberts; Abhay K.; Geraldine Connolly; Bob Hicok; George Bilgere; Jeannine M. Pitas; Jorie Graham; Lesley Nneka Arimah; Poets Commemorate China's Nanking Massacre; Arielle Saiber
  Poet and the Poem 2018 Series
  Zeina Hashem Beck; Sherwin Bitsui; Linda Rodriguez; George Wallace; Bojan Louis; Margo Jefferson; Anna Lawton; Lauren Camp; Diane Wilbon Parks; Rachel Corbett; Patrick Washington; Mike Maggio; Holly Bass; Terry Blackhawk; Frank X Walker; Shauna Morgan; Tracy K Smith; Matthew Hittinger; Platos Symposium; Fleda Brown; Eli Gottlieb; Reuben Jackson; Kevin Gordon; Emily Fragos; Sandra Evans Falconer
  Poet and the Poem 2017 Series
  The Literary Review Fairleigh Dickinson University; Harteis' Appreciation of Cavalieri's "Other Voices Other Lives."; Jim Reese; Mark McMorris; E. Ethelbert Miller; Collective Voices; Elizabeth Hazen; Judith McCombs; Joseph Ross; Hayes Davis; Indran Amirthanayagam; Evie Shockley; Dai Sil Kim-Gibson; Barbara Goldberg and Nancy Carlson; Hope Snyder; Laura Shovan
  - Website: The Poet and the Poem at the Library of Congress, 2016; Series 16